Finding Aid for the S.A. Griffin collection of underground poetry, Scott Wannberg, and The Carma Bums LSC.2248
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Scott Wannberg papers, circa 1969-2014 (Box 194, Box 235, Box 293, Box 294, Box 295, Box 296, Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 300, Box 301, Box 302, Box 303, Box 304, Box 305, Box 306, Box 307, Box 308, Box 309, Box 310, Box 311, Box 312, Box 313, Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 317, Box 318, Box 31
  - Writings by Wannberg (Box 293, Box 294, Box 295, Box 296, Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 300, Box 301, Box 302, Box 303)
    - Serials (Box 301, Box 302, Box 303)
      - Aversion, no. 3. Chatsworth., 1986 May (Box 301, Folder 2)
        "Selfish Man" appears in this issue.
      - Aversion, no. 6. Chatsworth., 1986 Fall/Winter (Box 301, Folder 2)
        "They Got" appears in this issue.
      - Beyond Baroque Magazine, v. 26, no. 2., 2004 (Box 301, Folder 3)
        "Emily Dickinson In Iraq" appears in this issue.
      - Beyond Baroque Dinner Program. Venice., 2014 April 6 (Box 301, Folder 4)
        This 4th Annual George Drury Smith Awards Dinner program features Wannberg's "when dancing became legal."
      - Birthstone, no. 4. San Francisco., 1978 (Box 301, Folder 5)
        "Cocktail Hour" appears in this issue.
      - blue satellite, v. 2, no. 1. Venice., 1995 September (Box 301, Folder 6)
        "Iguana" and "63" appear in this issue.
      - Blue Satellite, v. 5, no. 1. Burbank., 1998 September (Box 301, Folder 6)
        "No Contract" appears in this issue.
      - Blue Satellite, v. 5, no. 2. Burbank., 1999 February (Box 301, Folder 6)
        "Scarecrow" appears in this issue.
      - Caffeine, no. 5. Woodland Hills., 1993 (Box 301, Folder 7)
        "The Burden" appears in this issue.
      - Country Connections, v. 3, no. 2. Mt. Pines., 1994 April (Box 301, Folder 8)
        "I Think The Movie We Are In Will End Soon" appears in this issue.
      - Desert Shovel Review, v. 1, no. 1. Santa Fe., 2006 (Box 301, Folder 9)
        "Heads of State" appears in this issue.
      - Dufus! San Pedro., 1998 (Box 301, Folder 10)
        "The Craft of Writing" appears in this issue.
      - Found & Lost Magascene, v. 1, no. 0., circa 2010 (Box 301, Folder 11)
        "Loosen Up" appears in this issue.
      - Fuck This Shit. Los Angeles., 1996 (Box 301, Folder 12)
        "Long Time In Which You Can Bleed" appears in this issue.
      - Haight Ashbury Literary Journal, v. 16, no.1. San Francisco., 1997 (Box 301, Folder 13)
        "Guardian Angel To Dogs" appears in this issue.
      - High Performance #38, v. 10, no. 2. Los Angeles., 1987 (Box 301, Folder 14)
        This magazine includes the article, "L.A.'s Poet Innovators: Voices From the New Ellis Island" which features Geraldine Keams, Scott Wannberg, Manazar Gamboa, and Kamau Daaood. Wannberg's "Someday" is printed on page 42 below a photograph of him at Dutton's.
      - Humanities/AITIA, v. 28, no. 2. Farmingdale., 2009 (Box 301, Folder 15)
        "Call And Response...Swing Your Partner" appears in this issue.
      - Insomnia, v. 3, no. 2. Whittier., 1994 Spring (Box 302, Folder 1)
        "Everybody Loves A Wound," "The Hoedown," and "Briggs" appear in this issue.
      - Insomnia, v. 3, no. 4. Whittier., 1994 Fall (Box 302, Folder 1)
        "Don't Judge the Cola" appears in this issue.
      - Insomnia, v. 4, no. 2. Whittier., 1995 Summer (Box 302, Folder 1)
        "The Paltry River in the Broken House of Man" appears in this issue.
      - Letterhead, v. 2. Buffalo., 2008 (Box 302, Folder 2)
        "Lunchmeat of the Poor" appears in this issue.
      - Lummox Journal, v. 6, no. 8. San Pedro., 2000 August (Box 302, Folder 3)
        "Charles Bukowski, Mountain Man (from the pages of Americana, a new hero is born)" appears in this issue.
      - Lummox Journal, v. 7, no. 4. San Pedro., 2001 April (Box 302, Folder 3)
        "Colorado River Song" appears in this issue.
      - Lummox Journal, v. 10, no. 5. San Pedro., 2004 September/October (Box 302, Folder 3)
        "The Dove Has Fangs" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 2. New York., 2008 Spring (Box 302, Folder 4)
        "The Foot of Hillary Clinton" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 3. New York., 2009 Spring (Box 302, Folder 4)
        "The Doctor Bill Pisses Blood On My Carpet" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 4. New York., 2010 Spring (Box 302, Folder 4)
        "Courteous Debutant Has Sad Teeth" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 5. New York., 2011 (Box 302, Folder 5)
        "Killer Bats of Love" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 6. New York., 2012 (Box 302, Folder 5)
        One DadaJanDada CD.
        "Tell God To Go And Fetch His Gun," "11 Items Or Less," "Sparky Just Has To Ask The Following Question...," and "Point Of No Return" appear in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 7. New York., 2013 (Box 302, Folder 5)
        "Seen It Coming" appears in this issue.
      - Maintenant, v. 1, no. 8. New York., 2014 (Box 302, Folder 5)
        "Giant Mayonnaise Sandwiches" appears in this issue.
      - Meat, no. 14. Los Angeles., 2013 August 19 (Box 302, Folder 6)
        This issue is dedicated to the the work of Wannberg and features four of his poems.
      - Momentum. Los Angeles., 1978 Spring, Summer, Fall (Box 302, Folder 7)
        "Epilogue" and "Dance It" appear in this issue.
      - Moon & Sun Review, no. 1. Venice., 2014 Spring (Box 303, Folder 1)
      - Next, v. 3, no. 6. Long Beach., 1996 August (Box 303, Folder 2)
        Wannberg and Griffin, Mike M. Mollett, and Doug Knott of The Carma Bums are interviewed in this issue.
      - Ouija Madness, no. 1. Los Angeles., 1981 (Box 303, Folder 3)
        This issue devotes three pages to Wannberg's poetry.
      - Ouija Madness, no. 2. Los Angeles., 1982 (Box 303, Folder 3)
        Wannberg's feature on Whit Bissell appears in this issue.
      - Page Smith. Santa Cruz., 1996 April (Box 303, Folder 4)
        This catalog for Smith's "In Praise of Greatness" exhibition features Wannberg's "The Historian Singer."
      - A Piece of Paper. Los Angeles., 1990 March 23 (Box 303, Folder 5)
        "Fullerton Blowout" appears in this issue.
      - Poesy, no. 39. Santa Cruz., 2012 (Box 303, Folder 6)
        This issue is dedicated to Scott Wannberg and features "the rain came down collect."
      - Sabado Gigante, no. 13/14. Hollywood., undated (Box 303, Folder 7)
        This issue of the OnTarget Independent Writer's Project features "Down At Pic 'N' Save Looking For A Marked-Down Country To Hide Out In."
      - Screen Actor, v. 28, no. 2., 1989 Summer (Box 303, Folder 8)
        This issue features "Cassavetes" and is inscribed by Wannberg.
      - sgraffito, v. 3, no. 2. Marina del Rey., 1994 Summer (Box 303, Folder 9)
        "Taken In" appears in this issue.
      - (Sic), v. 3, no. 1. North Hollywood., 1996 (Box 303, Folder 10)
        "A Drunk Kid With Money" appears in this issue.
      - (Sic) Random Vice & Verse, v. 1, no. 18. Los Angeles., 1992 March 27 (Box 303, Folder 10)
        "Killing Season" appears in this issue.
      - Tower 11, no. 1. Pacific Palisades., 1990 (Box 303, Folder 11)
        "The Raymond Carver Two Step" appears in this issue.
      - Tower 11. Pacific Palisades., 1990 (Box 303, Folder 11)
        "A Rumor Talked Loudly Inside Your Head" and "Two Highways Walking Sidesaddle In Your Inability To Move" appear in this issue.
      - Tsunami, v. 3, no. 1. Venice., 1990 Winter (Box 303, Folder 12)
        "The White Page" appears in this issue.
      - URTHKIN. Los Angeles., 1979 (Box 303, Folder 13)
        "Marriage" appears in this issue.
      - Zen Baby, no. 19. Santa Cruz., circa 2008 (Box 303, Folder 14)
        "Sway Along The Dance Floor" appears in this issue.
      - Zygote In My Coffee, no. 6. Kettering., 2009 Winter (Box 303, Folder 15)
        "Kama Sutra Hard On Blues" appears in this issue.
      - ZYZZYVA, v. 10, no. 1. San Francisco., 1994 Spring (Box 303, Folder 16)
        "When The Colleagues Run Out Of Ammunition" appears in this issue.
  - Writings collected by Wannberg (Box 304, Box 305, Box 306, Box 307, Box 308, Box 309, Box 310, Box 311, Box 312, Box 313, Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 317, Box 318, Box 319, Box 320, Box 321, Box 322, Box 323, Box 324, Box 325, Box 326, Box 327)
    Writings collected by Wannberg include monographs, which are organized alphabetically by author, and serials, which are organized alphabetically by title.
    - Monographs (Box 304, Box 305, Box 306, Box 307, Box 308, Box 309, Box 310, Box 311, Box 312, Box 313, Box 314, Box 315, Box 316, Box 317, Box 318, Box 319, Box 320, Box 321, Box 322, Box 323, Box 324, Box 325)
      Monographs collected by Wannberg may be found in boxes 304-325.
      Books from Scott Wannberg's library that were originally donated with the S.A. Griffin papers have been individually cataloged in the UCLA Library online catalog. Records for these items may be found by searching the Special Coll/Archive SPAC "SALA" using the Advanced search tab in the Library catalog, or keyword searching "Books from the Library of S.A. Griffin".
    - Serials (Box 326, Box 327)
      Serials collected by Wannberg, which are alphabetized by title, are comprised of poetry related journals, zines and magazines, including The Alley Cat Readings, Black Ace, Laugh Literary and Man The Humping Guns, and Sparring With Beatnik Ghosts.
      - The Alley Cat Readings, no. 2. Hermosa Beach., 1976 February 15 and March 14 (Box 326, Folder 1)
        Poems from readings at the Alley Cat Restaurant edited by Marcus J. Grapes and Michael Andrews. Poets include Wanda Coleman, Doraine Poretz, Deena Metzger, and Michael C. Ford.
      - The Alley Cat Readings, no. 4. Hermosa Beach., 1976 June (Box 326, Folder 1)
        Readings selected from three readings in the Summer of 1976 at the Alley Cat Restaurant. Groups represented in these readings are the Venice Poetry Workshop, The Women's Workshop, and the Radical Poets Cooperative. Authors include Frances Dean Smith, Bob Flanagan, and Michael Andrews.
      - The Alley Cat Readings, no. 5. Hermosa Beach., 1976 September (Box 326, Folder 1)
        Work presented at 1976 readings at Brighella's Alley Cat Restaurant in Hermosa Beach. Authors include Kita Shantiris, Curtis Lyle, and Eloise Klein Healy.
      - Armin Mueller-Stahl. Eutin., 2011 (Box 326, Folder 2)
        This Ostholstein-Museum exhibition catalog is signed by the artist.
      - Black Ace, no. 7. Los Angeles., 2002 (Box 326, Folder 3)
        This Black Ace/Temple of Man publication is inscribed to Scott from Tony Scibella.
      - California State Poetry Quarterly: CQ, v. 14, no. 3. Los Angeles., 1987-1988 Winter (Box 326, Folder 4)
        This official publication of the California State Poetry Society includes work by Charles Bukowski, Laurel Ann Bogen, and Amy Uyematsu.
      - Laugh Literary and Man The Humping Guns, v. 1, no. 2. Los Angeles., 1969 (Box 327, Folder 1)
        This "Dirty Poems For Your Suicide Lives" poetry publication is edited by Charles Bukowski and Neeli Cherry. This issue features art by Bukowski and Cherry.
      - Laugh Literary and Man The Humping Guns, v. 1, no. 3. Los Angeles., 1971 February (Box 327, Folder 1)
        This poetry publication is edited by Charles Bukowski and Neeli Cherry.
      - Lummox Journal, v. 9, no. 9. San Pedro., 2003 September (Box 327, Folder 2)
        Laura Stamps interviews Lyn Lifshin in this issue.
      - A New Year's Greeting. Santa Rosa., 1998 (Box 327, Folder 3)
        This publication features poetry by Charles Bukowski and is 45/226 printed for the friends of Black Sparrow Press.
      - A New Year's Greeting. Santa Rosa., 2002 (Box 327, Folder 3)
        This publication features poetry by Charles Bukowski and is 108/176 printed for the friends of Black Sparrow Press.
      - Poetry, v. 195, no. 5. Chicago., 2010 February (Box 327, Folder 4)
      - Poetry, v. 195, no. 6. Chicago., 2010 March (Box 327, Folder 4)
      - Poetry, v. 196, no. 1. Chicago., 2010 April (Box 327, Folder 4)
      - Poetry, v. 196, no. 2. Chicago., 2010 May (Box 327, Folder 4)
      - Poetry, v. 196, no. 3. Chicago., 2010 June (Box 327, Folder 5)
      - Poetry, v. 196, no. 4. Chicago., 2010 July/August (Box 327, Folder 5)
      - Poetry, v. 196, no. 5. Chicago., 2010 September (Box 327, Folder 5)
      - Poetry, v. 197, no. 1. Chicago., 2010 October (Box 327, Folder 5)
      - Poetry, v. 197, no. 2. Chicago., 2010 November (Box 327, Folder 6)
      - Poetry, v. 197, no. 3. Chicago., 2010 December (Box 327, Folder 6)
      - Poetry, v. 197, no. 4. Chicago., 2011 January (Box 327, Folder 6)
      - Re)verb, no. 4. Garden Grove., 2006 Winter (Box 327, Folder 7)
      - Screen Actor, v. 52, no. 3. Los Angeles., 2011 Fall (Box 327, Folder 8)
        Wannberg is remembered on page 77 of the Screen Actors Guild "In Memoriam" section: August 19, 2011.
      - Sparring With Beatnik Ghosts, v. 2, no. 1. Santa Cruz., 2011 Fall (Box 327, Folder 9)
        This anthology features artwork by S.A. Griffin.
  - Correspondence (Box 328, Folder 1-5)
    Correspondence is arranged in its existing order and includes letters to Wannberg from Michael C. Ford, S.A. Griffin, Ron Maxson, David McIntire, Mike M. Mollett, OngoingDancers, Page Smith, and Vickie Trancho. The Maxson file includes music demos by Joanne Nilan. These files also include Wannberg's address and phone lists. Wannberg's poetry may be found throughout these letters and lists.
    Box 328, Folder 4: Three CD-Rs.
  - Galleys (Box 328, Folder 6-11)
    Galleys and proofs are arranged chronologically for the following works by Wannberg: The Electric Yes Indeed!, The Unforeseen Death Of My T.V., The War, The Decider, and Let Everybody Come In. Materials also include a folder of Psychedelic Coloring Book art, The Unforeseen Death Of My T.V. typescript, and color photographs of Wannberg and Griffin on the road.
  - Artwork, undated, circa 1994, 2004, 2007, 2013 (Box 194, Folder 10, Box 329, Folder 1-3, Box 235)
    The artwork is arranged in its existing order and includes a framed drawing by historian Page Smith, a close friend of Wannberg's, and a framed painting by Georgia Griffin.
    Box 194: One Richard Hansen Mimeo Gathering poster signed by Hansen and the Sal Mimeo & The Process Rebels Without Applause Tour of Words poets: John Dorsey, S.A. Griffin, Bill Roberts, David Smith, and Scott Wannberg (2007).
    Box 235: One framed Artist's Proof of chickens by Page Smith which is inscribed to Wannberg by Smith and a color memorial painting of Wannberg by Vickie Trancho which is inscribed to Griffin (2013).
    Box 329: One framed painting of a dog entitled "Sparky" by Georgia Griffin (1989). S.A. Griffin's original collages for Wannberg's People Just Aren't broadside, and Griffin's Bukowski To The Curb broadside (circa 1994). A Phil Nieman For President sign by Wannberg (2004).
  - Memorabilia, 1976-2015 (Box 329, Folder 4-19, Box 194, Folder 11)
    Wannberg's memorabilia is arranged chronologically and includes photographs, Sam Peckinpah ephemera, gig flyers, performance programs, and music.
    Box 194: Poster with eight color photos of Wannberg eating a 5 pound roast on a dare at San Francisco State University. Many of the photos show Wannberg eating the roast with a sword (1976). One Three's Company ink and colored pencil Western drawing by Weeks inscribed "Here's To You Sam Peckinpah" was a gift to Wannberg from Sam Peckinpah's son Matthew.
    Box 329: Wannberg's memorabilia includes family photographs, Three Fools For April signed photograph by Viggo Mortensen, a photo of Paul Harper from Sam Peckinpah's "The Wild Bunch" inscribed to Scott by Harper, gig flyers, performance programs, John's of Bleeker Street 2011 calendar, Joanne Nilan poetry/songs, a Mike Bruner on KXLU Spoken Words CD, two CDs for Scott from Joanne Nilan's birthday, and ephemera.
    Wannberg memorial related memorabilia includes clippings, certificates from the City Council of Santa Monica, "The Poet Is Dead ... Long Live The Poet..." pieces by Neil Taylor aka Skooter, Beyond Baroque "Liberation The Big Guy Flies" celebration poster by Martin Gunsaullus, Scott Wannberg (February 20, 1953-August 19, 2011) memorial stickers, Beyond Baroque calendars that feature its dedication of the Scott Wannberg Memorial Bookstore and Poetry Lounge, correspondence with the Walt Whitman Birthplace Association concerning the placement of a Scott Wannberg commemorative brick within the Poetry Circle, a Vagabond certificate signed by founder Mark Lipman, popcorn bags, and broadsides from the Beyond Baroque dedication.
    Box 329, Folder 4: One CD-R of Dudley Martin family photographs.
    Box 329, Folder 11: Three CD-Rs of music and poetry, one of Mike Bruner on KXLU and two of Joanne's Birthday.